<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stock Market on Fincz Finance Blog</title><link>/tags/stock-market/</link><description>Recent content in Stock Market on Fincz Finance Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2020-{year} Fincz. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/stock-market/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DCF Valuation Method</title><link>/dcf-valuation-method/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/dcf-valuation-method/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="dcf-method-of-valuation">DCF Method of Valuation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>कंपनी के शेयर की वैल्यूएशन पता करने के लिए हम जिस तकनीक का इस्तेमाल करेंगे उसे कहते हैं &lt;strong>Discounted Cash Flow (DCF) Method of Valuation&lt;/strong> । इस तकनीक में फ्यूचर के कैश फ्लो के नजरिए से कंपनी के शेयर की सही कीमत का अंदाजा लगाया जाता है।&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="शयर-क-सह-कमत">शेयर की सही कीमत&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>हमने इक्विटी रिसर्च के लिए वीडियो बना कर पहले ही आप को बता दिया है। पहला हिस्सा जहां हमने कंपनी के बिजनेस को और दूसरा हिस्सा जहां हमने कंपनी के फाइनेंसियल परफॉर्मेंस को देखा। इक्विटी रिसर्च का तीसरा हिस्सा है, कंपनी के शेयर की वैल्यूएशन पता करना। लेकिन यह तभी करिए जब आप पहले दो हिस्से में कंपनी के बिजनेस के बारे में पूरी तरह कॉंफिडेंट हो।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Long-Term Stock Selection Checklist</title><link>/stock-selection-checklist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/stock-selection-checklist/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="long-term-stock-selection-checklist">Long-Term Stock Selection Checklist&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Many investors are confused when it comes to the stock market. they have trouble figuring out which stocks are good long-term buys and which ones aren&amp;rsquo;t. To invest for the long term, not only do you have to look at certain indicators, but you also have to remain focused on your long-term goals, be disciplined, and understand your overall investment objectives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am sharing my own checklist you can copy and can modify according to your way&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>25 Stock market terms for beginners</title><link>/stock-market-terminology/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/stock-market-terminology/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I first entered the share market world, I spend enormous time googling the basic stock market terms which are used in the share market.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although there are many terminologies which a stock market trader should know, they are a handful of stock market terms that are used very often.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This basic domain knowledge of these stock market terms is really important if you want to enter the stock market to succeed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>नए लोग स्टॉक बाज़ार में ऑनलाइन ट्रेडिंग कैसे करें</title><link>/trading-kaise-karte-hain/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/trading-kaise-karte-hain/</guid><description>&lt;p>अगर आपको स्मार्ट तरिके से जल्दी अमीर होना हैं तो आज के वक्त शेअर मार्केट हि एकमात्र करियर हैं जहां आप यह आसानी से अमीर बन सकते हों&lt;/p>
&lt;p>आज हम आपको बताने वाले हैं ट्रेडिंग क्या है, ट्रेडिंग कितने प्रकार के होते हैं, ट्रेडिंग अकाउंट क्या है, आज के इस पोस्ट में आपको वो सब चीजें बताने वाला हूं जिससे आपको ट्रेडिंग की अच्छी खासी जानकारी मिल जाएंगी और आसानी से पैसे कमा सकते हो।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>म्यूचुअल फंड में निवेश कैसे करें</title><link>/mutual-fund-investment-in-hindi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/mutual-fund-investment-in-hindi/</guid><description>&lt;p>क्या आप म्यूचुअल फंड्स की स्कीम में निवेश करते हैं? निवेश करने से पहले म्यूचुअल फंड को जान लेना बहुत जरूरी है। इससे आपको निवेश के फैसले लेने में मदद मिलेगी आइए जानते हैं क्या है म्यूचुअल फंड? हम आपको यह भी बता रहे हैं कि आप म्यूचुअल फंड में कैसे निवेश कर सकते हैं?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>तो यहां पर ‘शीर्ष 10 म्यूचुअल फंड’ के बारे में जानकारी दी जा रही है, जिससे आप मदद ले सकते हैं। अगर आप एक नए म्यूचुअल फंड निवेशक हैं, तो आपके दिमाग में यह सवाल हमेशा आता होगा कि ‘कहां पर निवेश करें और ‘हमें कितना निवेश करना चाहिए?’&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>शेयर बाजार में प्रयोग होने वाले सबसे महत्वपूर्ण 20+ शब्द और उनके अर्थ</title><link>/share-market-terminology/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/share-market-terminology/</guid><description>&lt;p>शेयर मार्केट में प्रयोग होने वाले शब्द और उनके अर्थ जिनसे आप जान सकें शेयर बाज़ार की भाषा जिससे कि आपको इस बाजार और इसकी शब्दावली को समझने में आसानी होगी।&lt;/p>
&lt;p>कई प्रकार के शब्द जो कि शेयर बाजार में प्रयोग किए जाते हैं बाजार कि ट्रेडिंग के बारे में, शेयरों के बारे में या कम्पनियों के बारे में जिनका अर्थ हमें मालूम नहीं होता है। आज समझेंगे शेयर बाजार की भाषा जिससे इस बाजार को समझने में और भी आसानी होगी।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Basic knowledge of share market</title><link>/share-market-basic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/share-market-basic/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="basic-knowledge-of-share-market">Basic knowledge of share market&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today in this article we will get some basic information related to the share market, like what is a share, why does a company need a share, how is a company&amp;rsquo;s stock list, how does a company earn money in the stock market, and we share shares. How to earn money by investing in the market. What is SEBI, what is stock exchange, what is Nifty and SENSEX, how can we buy and sell shares in the stock market, do we have to pay tax in the stock market.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is share market</title><link>/share-market/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/share-market/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="information-about-share-market">Information about share market&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this article, we will know some important things related to share market, out of which what is share market.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How to start share market, how to invest in share market, who is called share holder, why company sells shares, what is an investor, how to buy and sell shares.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Intraday Trading, Swing Trading, Long Term Investment, Trading Vs Investment What is better, How to buy Shares, What is Demat Account, Advantages of Demat Account, How to Open Demat Account, How to Lose in Share Market&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>