<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Types of Mutual Fund on Fincz Finance Blog</title><link>/tags/types-of-mutual-fund/</link><description>Recent content in Types of Mutual Fund on Fincz Finance Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2020-{year} Fincz. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/types-of-mutual-fund/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>lump sum investment in mutual fund</title><link>/lump-sum-investment-in-mutual-fund/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/lump-sum-investment-in-mutual-fund/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-lumpsum-investment">What is Lumpsum Investment&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A lumpsum investment is a method where an investment in a mutual fund is made in one go. They are usually made in great amounts, unlike SIPs which are small investment amounts at regular intervals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lumpsum investments do not occur at regular intervals, instead, one can make these at their disposal. For example, let’s say Priya wanted to investment Rs.1,00,000 in a mutual fund.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She didn’t want to split the amount to be put in small investments at regular intervals, since she had surplus money lying idle in her bank account. As Priya is well aware of inflation risk, she decided to put all of it in one go.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Is A Mutual Fund And How Does It Work</title><link>/what-is-mutual-fund/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/what-is-mutual-fund/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today in this article we will talk about What Is a Mutual Fund and How Does It Work,
apart from this, we will talk about more things related to it like investment in Mutual Fund,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Types of Mutual Funds, and Advantages and Disadvantages of Mutual Funds, the benefits of investing in a Mutual Fund will be known in this article.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So let’s start by reading this article carefully about some basic information related to Mutual Fund for Beginners and get good information about What Is a Mutual Fund and How Does It Work.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>