<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Fincz Finance Blog</title><link>/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Fincz Finance Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2020-{year} Fincz. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 08:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Insurance Product Questions and Answers</title><link>/insurence-product-questions-and-answers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/insurence-product-questions-and-answers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Interviewer: Good morning/afternoon [Candidate&amp;rsquo;s Name]. Thank you for taking the time to interview with us. Before we start, could you please tell us a bit about your experience?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Candidate: [Candidate&amp;rsquo;s response, typically covering their experience, skills, and reasons for interest]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interviewer: That&amp;rsquo;s great. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with some technical questions:
Please Rate yourself on a Scale of 1 to 10 for your top skills&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="java-questions-and-answers">Java Questions and Answers&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-what-are-the-differences-between-equals-and-hashcode-methods">1. What are the differences between &lt;code>equals()&lt;/code> and &lt;code>hashCode()&lt;/code> methods?&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;code>equals()&lt;/code>: It is a method used to compare the equality of two objects in Java. By default, it checks for reference equality&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Java PGSql Interview Questions</title><link>/java-pgsql-interview-questions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/java-pgsql-interview-questions/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="interview-start-script">Interview Start Script&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Introduction:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Interviewer:&lt;/strong> &amp;ldquo;Hello [Candidate&amp;rsquo;s Name], thank you for joining us today. How are you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Candidate:&lt;/strong> [Response]&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Interviewer:&lt;/strong> &amp;ldquo;Great to hear! My name is [Your Name], and I will be conducting your interview today. We appreciate your interest in the [Position] role at [Company Name].&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Interview Overview:&lt;/strong>
4. &lt;strong>Interviewer:&lt;/strong> &amp;ldquo;To give you a brief overview, today&amp;rsquo;s interview will consist of a few sections. We&amp;rsquo;ll start with some questions about your background and experience. Then, we&amp;rsquo;ll move on to technical questions related to Java, PostgreSQL, and full-stack development. Finally, we will discuss some situational questions to understand how you approach various scenarios.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Itechf Interview Preparation</title><link>/itechf-interview-prep/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/itechf-interview-prep/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction-5-minutes">Introduction (5 minutes)&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Welcome and Context:&lt;/strong> Hi everyone, thanks for joining! Today, I&amp;rsquo;m here to share some insights and tips to help you for your upcoming interviews with Itechf they are mostly using Java, Spring Boot, and PostgreSQL I recently interviewed and now working for itechf.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>First Question as usual you may be asked to give your introduction. After that, they will ask you about the previous project, your role and responsibilities in it, and what work you have done.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Coding Standards and Guidelines</title><link>/coding-standards-and-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/coding-standards-and-guidelines/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="general-coding-guideline">General coding guideline&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="variable-name">variable name&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Should not start with an underscore (_) and ($)
Use camelCase
Should have the meaning full name
Common names for temporary variables are I,j,k,m,n for integers and c,d,e for chars&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="constant-naming">constant naming&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Should not start with an underscore and $
Use UPPER_CASE
Separate by _&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="avoid-hard-coding">Avoid hard coding&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t Hard code any data/value within your code
If it&amp;rsquo;s a text or numeric value that needs to be used in your application then convert that into constant&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Project Meeting Common Sentences</title><link>/meeting-discussion-questions-and-answers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/meeting-discussion-questions-and-answers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="common-agile-development-meeting-sentences">Common Agile Development Meeting Sentences&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-daily-standup-updates">&lt;strong>1. Daily Standup Updates&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Q:&lt;/strong> What did you work on yesterday?
&lt;strong>A:&lt;/strong> Yesterday, I focused on optimizing the database queries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Q:&lt;/strong> What&amp;rsquo;s your plan for today?
&lt;strong>A:&lt;/strong> Today, I&amp;rsquo;ll start implementing the new user authentication feature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Q:&lt;/strong> Are there any blockers you&amp;rsquo;re facing?
&lt;strong>A:&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;m waiting for approval on the design mockups, which is blocking my progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2-sprint-planning">&lt;strong>2. Sprint Planning&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Q:&lt;/strong> What user stories will you be tackling this sprint?
&lt;strong>A:&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking on the user profile and settings stories.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Project Migration Interview Questions and Answers</title><link>/project-migration-questions-and-answers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/project-migration-questions-and-answers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="project-migration">Project Migration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Migrating from a monolithic architecture to a microservices architecture involves careful planning, design, and execution. Here are the steps to guide you through the process:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Assessment and Planning:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Understand the monolithic application&amp;rsquo;s architecture, components, dependencies, and pain points.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Define the goals and reasons for migrating to microservices. Identify the expected benefits.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Assess the feasibility of breaking down the monolith into microservices considering technical challenges and potential advantages.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Identify Microservices:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Previous Project Questions and Answers</title><link>/previous-project-questions-and-answers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/previous-project-questions-and-answers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="previous-project-questions-for-a-12-year-software-developer">Previous Project Questions for a 12-year Software Developer&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-what-are-the-key-features-you-implemented-in-your-last-project">1. What are the key features you implemented in your last project?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I implemented a user authentication system, data encryption, and a responsive user interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2-how-did-you-handle-scalability-in-your-previous-project">2. How did you handle scalability in your previous project?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I designed the application using a microservices architecture and employed horizontal scaling techniques.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="3-describe-a-challenging-bug-you-encountered-and-how-you-resolved-it">3. Describe a challenging bug you encountered and how you resolved it.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I faced a memory leak issue caused by improper object disposal. I used a memory profiler to identify the problem and manually released the resources, fixing the bug.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sample Interview Questions and Answers</title><link>/interview-discussion-questions-and-answers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/interview-discussion-questions-and-answers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="interview-debrief">Interview Debrief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Let me tell you about the interview process. First of all the interview will be in video mode.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There can be three people taking the interview. First Question as usual you may be asked to give your introduction. After that, they will ask you about the previous project, your role and responsibilities in it, and what work you have done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They can ask some questions about the work you have done in the previous project and whatever you will explain. And will put up questions one after the other from the same.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ReactJs Questions and Answers</title><link>/reactjs-questions-and-answers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/reactjs-questions-and-answers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="reactjs-questions-and-answers">ReactJs Questions and Answers&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-what-is-reactjs">1. What is ReactJS?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>ReactJS is a JavaScript library used for building user interfaces. It allows developers to create reusable UI components and efficiently update them when the underlying data changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2-what-is-jsx">2. What is JSX?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>JSX is a syntax extension for JavaScript used in React. It allows developers to write HTML-like code within JavaScript, making it easier to describe the structure and appearance of UI components.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Features in Java 17</title><link>/java17-questions-and-answers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/java17-questions-and-answers/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="java-17">Java 17&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Java 17 LTS is the latest long-term support release for the Java SE platform. JDK 17 binaries are free to use in production and free to redistribute, at no cost, under the Oracle No-Fee Terms and Conditions License, where LTS stands for long-term support. It was released on September 15, 2021.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-what-are-the-new-features-introduced-in-java-17">1. What are the new features introduced in Java 17?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Yes everybody is crazy for major updates in this version in order to transduce workflow but developers should be disappointed as there are not such big release update version checks as we can see from the JDK enhancement proposal commonly referred to as JEPS as provided below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AWS Cloud Questions and Answers</title><link>/aws-questions-and-answers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/aws-questions-and-answers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="aws-cloud-questions-and-answers">AWS Cloud Questions and Answers&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="q1-what-is-aws-cloudformation-and-how-does-it-work">Q1. What is AWS CloudFormation, and how does it work?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>AWS CloudFormation is a service that allows you to define and provision infrastructure resources in a declarative manner. It uses templates written in YAML or JSON format to describe the desired state of your infrastructure.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="q2-what-is-aws-lambda-and-how-does-it-work">Q2. What is AWS Lambda, and how does it work?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>AWS Lambda is a serverless compute service that allows you to run your code without provisioning or managing servers. With Lambda, you can upload your code and specify the event sources that trigger its execution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Frequently Used Annotations in Spring Boot</title><link>/frequently-used-annotations-in-spring-boot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/frequently-used-annotations-in-spring-boot/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="frequently-used-annotations-in-spring-boot">Frequently Used Annotations in Spring Boot&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When it comes to developing applications using Spring Boot, there are several annotations that are commonly used. Here are some of the most frequently used annotations in Spring Boot:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-restcontroller">1. &lt;code>@RestController&lt;/code>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>@RestController&lt;/code> annotation is used to define a class as a RESTful controller. It combines the &lt;code>@Controller&lt;/code> and &lt;code>@ResponseBody&lt;/code> annotations, making it easier to create RESTful APIs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2-requestmapping">2. &lt;code>@RequestMapping&lt;/code>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>@RequestMapping&lt;/code> annotation is used to map HTTP requests to specific controller methods. It allows you to define the URL path and HTTP method for handling the requests.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Java Questions and Answers</title><link>/java-questions-and-answers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/java-questions-and-answers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="java-questions-and-answers">Java Questions and Answers&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="solid-design-principles">SOLID Design Principles&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>SOLID is an acronym that represents a set of five design principles aimed at improving software design and maintainability. Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief description of each principle:&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="1-single-responsibility-principle-srp">1. Single Responsibility Principle (SRP)&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A class should have only one reason to change.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It states that a class should have a single responsibility and should be focused on doing one thing well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This principle promotes modularity and makes classes easier to understand, test, and maintain.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="2-openclosed-principle-ocp">2. Open/Closed Principle (OCP)&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Software entities (classes, modules, functions) should be open for extension but closed for modification.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It suggests that code should be written in a way that new functionality can be added without modifying existing code.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This principle promotes code reusability, maintainability, and allows for easier integration of new features.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="3-liskov-substitution-principle-lsp">3. Liskov Substitution Principle (LSP)&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Subtypes must be substitutable for their base types.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It ensures that objects of a superclass can be replaced with objects of its subclass without affecting the correctness of the program.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This principle promotes code reuse and helps maintain a consistent and predictable behavior of objects in a hierarchy.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="4-interface-segregation-principle-isp">4. Interface Segregation Principle (ISP)&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Clients should not be forced to depend on interfaces they do not use.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It suggests that interfaces should be fine-grained and focused on specific client requirements.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This principle promotes decoupling, modularity, and prevents the problem of &amp;ldquo;fat&amp;rdquo; interfaces.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="5-dependency-inversion-principle-dip">5. Dependency Inversion Principle (DIP)&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>High-level modules should not depend on low-level modules; both should depend on abstractions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It states that the dependency should be on abstractions rather than concrete implementations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This principle promotes loose coupling, flexibility, and facilitates easier unit testing and modular design.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="java-language-basics">Java Language Basics&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>What is autoboxing and unboxing?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Microservices Questions and Answers</title><link>/microservices-questions-and-answers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/microservices-questions-and-answers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="microservices-questions">Microservices Questions&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-what-are-the-main-advantages-of-using-microservices-architecture">1. What are the main advantages of using microservices architecture?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Microservices architecture provides benefits such as improved scalability, fault isolation, independent deployment, technology diversity, and better team autonomy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2-how-do-microservices-communicate-with-each-other">2. How do microservices communicate with each other?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Microservices typically communicate through lightweight protocols such as HTTP/REST or messaging systems like RabbitMQ or Apache Kafka. API gateways and service registries can also be used for service discovery and communication.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="3-what-is-service-discovery-and-why-is-it-important-in-microservices">3. What is service discovery and why is it important in microservices?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Service discovery is the process of dynamically locating and registering services within a microservices architecture. It enables automatic service registration, health checks, load balancing, and allows services to find and communicate with each other without hard-coded dependencies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RESTful Web Service Questions and Answers</title><link>/restful-web-service-questions-and-answers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/restful-web-service-questions-and-answers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="restful-web-service-with-spring-boot-questions-and-short-answers">RESTful Web Service with Spring Boot Questions and Short Answers&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-what-is-rest">1. What is REST?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>REST (Representational State Transfer) is an architectural style for designing networked applications. It relies on the HTTP protocol and emphasizes stateless, client-server communication through standard CRUD operations (Create, Read, Update, Delete).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2-what-is-a-restful-web-service">2. What is a RESTful web service?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A RESTful web service is an implementation of the REST architecture that allows clients to interact with resources over the web using HTTP methods like GET, POST, PUT, and DELETE. It follows the principles of statelessness, uniform resource identification, and representation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spring Boot Questions and Answers</title><link>/spring-boot-questions-and-answers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/spring-boot-questions-and-answers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="spring-boot">Spring Boot:&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-what-is-spring-boot">1. What is Spring Boot?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Spring Boot is a Java framework that simplifies the development of Java applications by providing default configurations, dependency management, and production-ready features out of the box.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2-explain-the-key-features-of-spring-boot">2. Explain the key features of Spring Boot.&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Auto-configuration&lt;/strong>: Spring Boot automatically configures application components based on classpath settings and dependencies.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Starter dependencies&lt;/strong>: Spring Boot provides a set of curated dependencies that are commonly used together for specific functionalities.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Embedded server&lt;/strong>: Spring Boot comes with an embedded server (e.g., Tomcat, Jetty) that eliminates the need for deploying applications to a separate server.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Actuator&lt;/strong>: It provides production-ready features like health checks, metrics, and monitoring for applications.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Spring Boot CLI&lt;/strong>: Spring Boot Command Line Interface allows rapid prototyping and development using Groovy scripts.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="3-how-does-spring-boot-differ-from-the-spring-framework">3. How does Spring Boot differ from the Spring Framework?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Spring Boot builds on top of the Spring Framework and aims to simplify the configuration and setup process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>बिटकॉइन में निवेश करना चाहते हैं, जानिए क्या है तरीका</title><link>/bitcoin-me-invest-kaise-kare/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/bitcoin-me-invest-kaise-kare/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="बटकइन-कय-ह">बिटकॉइन क्या है&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>आम तौर पर यह तो हम सभी जानते है कि बिटकॉइन ( Bitcoin ) दुनिया का पहला क्रिप्टोकरेंसी (cryptocurrency) है। जिस पर ना किसी देश और ना ही किसी कंपनी का कंट्रोल है, यह एक डिजिटल करेंसी है। जिसे ना देखा और न ही छुआ जा सकता है।&lt;/p>
&lt;p>बिटकॉइन की वैल्यू तेजी से घटती वा बढ़ती रहती है जितनी इसकी डिमांड बढ़ती है इसकी वैल्यू भी बढ़ती जाती है और डिमांड कम होने पर वैल्यू भी कम हो जाती है। यह ब्लॉकचैन सिस्टम पर आधारित होता है। आज के समय में बिटकॉइन सबसे महंगा और सबसे सुरक्षित क्रिप्टोकरेंसी है इसलिए आज हम जानेंगे की बिटकॉइन में निवेश (Investment) कैसे करें।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Latest Finance Trends</title><link>/finance-trends/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/finance-trends/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today in this article we will talk about Latest Finance Trends&lt;/p>
&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="https://ssl.gstatic.com/trends_nrtr/2790_RC04/embed_loader.js">&lt;/script> 

&lt;h2>Web&lt;/h2>
1. Related Topics

&lt;script type="text/javascript"> trends.embed.renderExploreWidget("RELATED_TOPICS", {"comparisonItem":[{"geo":"IN","time":"today 1-m"}],"category":7,"property":""}, {"exploreQuery":"cat=7&amp;date=today%201-m&amp;geo=IN","guestPath":"https://trends.google.com:443/trends/embed/"}); &lt;/script>
2. Related Queries
&lt;script type="text/javascript"> trends.embed.renderExploreWidget("RELATED_QUERIES", {"comparisonItem":[{"geo":"IN","time":"today 1-m"}],"category":7,"property":""}, {"exploreQuery":"cat=7&amp;date=today%201-m&amp;geo=IN","guestPath":"https://trends.google.com:443/trends/embed/"}); &lt;/script>

&lt;h2>Youtube&lt;/h2>
1. Related Topics
&lt;script type="text/javascript"> trends.embed.renderExploreWidget("RELATED_TOPICS", {"comparisonItem":[{"geo":"IN","time":"today 1-m"}],"category":7,"property":"youtube"}, {"exploreQuery":"cat=7&amp;date=today%201-m&amp;geo=IN&amp;gprop=youtube","guestPath":"https://trends.google.com:443/trends/embed/"}); &lt;/script>
2. Related Queries
&lt;script type="text/javascript"> trends.embed.renderExploreWidget("RELATED_QUERIES", {"comparisonItem":[{"geo":"IN","time":"today 1-m"}],"category":7,"property":"youtube"}, {"exploreQuery":"cat=7&amp;date=today%201-m&amp;geo=IN&amp;gprop=youtube","guestPath":"https://trends.google.com:443/trends/embed/"}); &lt;/script></description></item><item><title>DCF Valuation Method</title><link>/dcf-valuation-method/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/dcf-valuation-method/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="dcf-method-of-valuation">DCF Method of Valuation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>कंपनी के शेयर की वैल्यूएशन पता करने के लिए हम जिस तकनीक का इस्तेमाल करेंगे उसे कहते हैं &lt;strong>Discounted Cash Flow (DCF) Method of Valuation&lt;/strong> । इस तकनीक में फ्यूचर के कैश फ्लो के नजरिए से कंपनी के शेयर की सही कीमत का अंदाजा लगाया जाता है।&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="शयर-क-सह-कमत">शेयर की सही कीमत&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>हमने इक्विटी रिसर्च के लिए वीडियो बना कर पहले ही आप को बता दिया है। पहला हिस्सा जहां हमने कंपनी के बिजनेस को और दूसरा हिस्सा जहां हमने कंपनी के फाइनेंसियल परफॉर्मेंस को देखा। इक्विटी रिसर्च का तीसरा हिस्सा है, कंपनी के शेयर की वैल्यूएशन पता करना। लेकिन यह तभी करिए जब आप पहले दो हिस्से में कंपनी के बिजनेस के बारे में पूरी तरह कॉंफिडेंट हो।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Long-Term Stock Selection Checklist</title><link>/stock-selection-checklist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/stock-selection-checklist/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="long-term-stock-selection-checklist">Long-Term Stock Selection Checklist&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Many investors are confused when it comes to the stock market. they have trouble figuring out which stocks are good long-term buys and which ones aren&amp;rsquo;t. To invest for the long term, not only do you have to look at certain indicators, but you also have to remain focused on your long-term goals, be disciplined, and understand your overall investment objectives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am sharing my own checklist you can copy and can modify according to your way&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>जानिए क्या है Sensex और कैसे घटता-बढ़ता है शेयर बाजार</title><link>/sensex-kya-hota-hai/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/sensex-kya-hota-hai/</guid><description>&lt;p>आज के लेख में हम बात करने वाले हैं सेंसेक्स क्या होता है? यदि आप शेयर मार्केट में थोड़ी बहुत भी रुचि रखते हैं। तो आपको शेयर मार्केट की कुछ इंर्पोटेंट टर्म्स का नॉलेज होना आवश्यक है।&lt;/p>
&lt;p>इन इंर्पोटेंट टर्म्स में से एक है। सेंसेक्स आपने कई बार टीवी चैनल पर, न्यूज़ पेपर पर और लोगों के मुंह से कई बार आपने सेंसेक्स के बारे में सुना है। सेंसेक्स इतने पॉइंट चढ़ गया या सेंसेक्स कितने पॉइंट टूट गया लेकिन इन सब का कोई मतलब नहीं रह जाता जब तक कि आपको यह पता नहीं है। कि सेंसेक्स क्या होता है और कैसे काम करता है।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>जानिए BSE और NSE क्या है इनके बीच क्या अंतर</title><link>/nse-aur-bse-me-kya-antar-hai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/nse-aur-bse-me-kya-antar-hai/</guid><description>&lt;p>आज के लेख में हम बात करने वाले हैं। BSE और NSE क्या है? और इनके बीच में क्या अंतर है? यह सवाल हर कोई जानता है जो शेयर मार्केट में इन्वेस्ट करता है। सब को यह मालूम है शेयर मार्केट में 2 स्टॉक एक्सचेंज होते हैं।&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BSE और NSE लेकिन BSE क्या है? और NSE क्या है? इन दोनों में क्या अंतर है कुछ लोगों को पता नहीं होता। आज हम आपको NSE और BSE क्या है? और इन दोनों के बीच क्या अंतर है? इस बारे में बताने वाले हैं तो चलिए बिना देरी किए जानते हैं NSE और BSE क्या है।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is Short Term Debt Funds and How They Work</title><link>/what-is-short-term-debt-fund/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/what-is-short-term-debt-fund/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today we will know what is a short term debt fund and how it works. If you shop in a grocery store. So you know that everything has a last date. Like vegetables can spoil in 1 day. Vegetables like Tomato, Began, remain fresh for 3 to 4 days. And onions, potatoes stay fresh for months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Debt funds work in the same way Debt funds are a lesson in Mutual Funds. So today in this article we will know what is short term debt fund, what are its advantages, what are its disadvantages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ट्रेडिंग अकाउंट क्या होता है और कैसे खोले</title><link>/trading-account-kya-hai/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/trading-account-kya-hai/</guid><description>&lt;p>आज हम जानेंगे ट्रेडिंग अकाउंट क्या है आप कैसे ट्रेडिंग अकाउंट खोल सकते हैं। ट्रेडिंग अकाउंट के क्या-क्या फायदे हैं, ट्रेडिंग कैसे करते हैं, ट्रेडिंग कितने प्रकार के होते हैं, बाजार में निवेश करने के लिए ट्रेडिंग अकाउंट क्यों जरूरी है?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ट्रेडिंग अकाउंट खुलवाने के लिए किन दस्तावेजों की जरूरत पड़ती है। और ट्रेडिंग अकाउंट खुलवाने के लिए कितने पैसे लगते हैं। आज हम इस आर्टिकल में आपको पूरी जानकारी देंगे चलिए शुरू करते हैं। ट्रेडिंग अकाउंट क्या है?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>डीमैट अकाउंट क्या है और कैसे खोले पूरी जानकारी</title><link>/demat-account-kya-hota-hain/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/demat-account-kya-hota-hain/</guid><description>&lt;p>क्या आपके मन में भी कभी यह सवाल आया होगा कि आखिरी डीमैट अकाउंट क्या है। डीमैट अकाउंट कैसे ओपन करें ऑनलाइन, डीमैट अकाउंट कैसे काम करता है, डीमैट अकाउंट के क्या फायदे हैं, और डीमैट अकाउंट के क्या नुकसान है।&lt;/p>
&lt;p>आपने इन सवालों को कई बार इंटरनेट पर सर्च किया है पर आपको एक आर्टिकल में इन सारे सवालों का जवाब नहीं मिला होगा। इसीलिए यह आर्टिकल लेकर आया हूं। जिसमें आपको डीमैट अकाउंट के जरिए लोग शेयर बाजार मैं डीमैट अकाउंट का किस तरह यूज करते हैं।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title> जानिए NPS कैलकुलेटर क्या है? किसे निवेश करना चाहिए और इसके फायदे क्या है</title><link>/national-pension-scheme-calculator/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/national-pension-scheme-calculator/</guid><description>&lt;p>उम्र के एक पड़ाव पर हम सभी को पैसों की आवश्यकता पड़ती है। जब हम अपने आर्थिक कार्यों से रिटायर हो जाएं तब हमें फाइनेंशियल सपोर्ट की आवश्यकता होती है। हम ये कतई नहीं चाहेंगे की 60 वर्ष की उम्र के बाद हमें काम करना पड़े। इसीलिए हमें समय रहते रिटायरमेंट प्लानिंग अवश्य करनी चाहिए।&lt;/p>
&lt;p>अब ज्यादातर सरकारी और प्राइवेट सेक्टर से जुड़े लोग पेंशन स्कीम में निवेश करना चाहते हैं, ताकि रिटायमेंट के बाद पैसों की दिक्कत न आए। ऐसे में उनके लिए सबसे बेहतर विकल्पों में से एक NPS स्कीम है।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sukanya Samriddhi Yojana Benefits</title><link>/sukanya-samriddhi-yojana-benefits/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/sukanya-samriddhi-yojana-benefits/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are the father of a daughter. So you must take this plan. This is a government scheme. Sukanya Samriddhi Yojana is a savings scheme supported by the Government of India keeping in mind the parents of the girl child. Under this scheme, parents are encouraged to create a fund for the future education and marriage expenses of the girl child.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="know-what-is-sukanya-samriddhi-yojana">Know what is Sukanya Samriddhi Yojana&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This scheme was started by the Prime Minister Shri Narendra Modi in the year 2015. This scheme is only for girls.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>बच्चों के बेहतर भविष्य के लिए अपनाएं ये 5 इन्वेस्टमेंट प्लान</title><link>/bacho-ke-liye-investment-in-hindi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/bacho-ke-liye-investment-in-hindi/</guid><description>&lt;p>आज के समय में बच्चों की पढ़ाई-लिखाई बेहद महंगी होती जा रही है। इसके अलावा दूसरे खर्च भी बढ़ते जा रहे हैं। जहां तक हायर एजुकेशन का सवाल है, इसमें बहुत ज्यादा खर्च करना पड़ता है।&lt;/p>
&lt;p>बच्चा जब 2 या 3 साल का होता है तो पैरेंट्स को उसके भविष्य की चिंता सताने लगती है। खासतौर से उसकी पढ़ाई को लेकर। ऐसे में बच्चे के माता पिता उसके लिए शुरू से ही बचत करना शुरू कर देते हैं। फाइनेंशियल प्‍लानिंग करते समय हमेशा बच्‍चों के फ्यूचर को लेकर ठोस फैसला करना चाहिए।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>बॉन्ड क्या हैं और बॉन्ड् में कैसे निवेश करें</title><link>/bond-kya-hai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/bond-kya-hai/</guid><description>&lt;p>आपने बॉन्ड के बारे में बात करते हुए बहुत लोगों के मुंह से सुना होगा इस पोस्ट में हम आपको बॉन्ड के बारे में बताएंगे बॉन्ड क्या होते हैं, बॉन्ड कैसे काम करते हैं, बॉन्ड कितना रिटर्न देते हैं?, बॉन्ड्स के फायदे और नुकसान, बॉन्ड्स के प्रकार, बॉन्ड्स में कैसे इन्वेस्ट करें, इसके बारे में आपको विस्तार पूर्वक जानकारी देंगे तो आइए आज जानने की कोशिश करते हैं कि आखिर यह बॉन्ड है क्या।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>बॉन्ड क्या हैं और बॉन्ड् में कैसे निवेश करें</title><link>/sabse-jyada-return-dene-wale-share/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/sabse-jyada-return-dene-wale-share/</guid><description>&lt;p>नमस्कार दोस्तों आज हम बात करेंगे सबसे ज्यादा रिटर्न देने वाले शेयर 2022 | sabse jada return dene vale share के बारे में share market मैं ऐसी बहुत सी कंपनियां हैं जो 1 साल या 6 महीने के अंदर बहुत ही जबरदस्त मल्टीबैगर्स रिटर्न कमा कर देती है&lt;/p>
&lt;p>और उन शेयर्स में निवेश करने के लिए लोग बहुत ही उतावले हो जाते हैं तो आज हम आपको ऐसे ही कुछ कंपनियों के बारे में बताएंगे जिन्होंने 1 साल और 6 महीने में बहुत ही जबरदस्त रिटर्न कमा कर दिया जिसे आप इस लेख को पढ़कर विचार पूर्वक उस कंपनी में निवेश कर सकते हो&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>what is ipo in share market</title><link>/what-is-ipo-in-share-market/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/what-is-ipo-in-share-market/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today in this article we will talk about what is ipo in share market, apart from this we will talk about more things related to it like How to invest in ipo, IPO full form in share market, IPO investment benefits, or ipo investment disadvantages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People these days are becoming tech-savvy, and with that, they are opening up to investing. The millennials are searching for more unique avenues to grow their money.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SIP क्या है इसके फायदे और नुकसान</title><link>/sip-kya-hai/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/sip-kya-hai/</guid><description>&lt;p>जैसा कि आप सभी जानते हैं कि कि आपने एसआईपी SIP के बारे में बात करते हुए बहुत लोगों के मुंह से सुना होगा SIP से जुड़े काफी पोस्ट आपने अपने मोबाइल या कंप्यूटर में देखे होंगे पर आप नहीं जानते SIP क्या है ,तो इस&lt;/p>
&lt;p>पोस्ट में हम आपको एसआईपी SIP के बारे में बताएंगे SIP की फुल फॉर्म क्या होती है, SIP क्या है इसके फायदे और नुकसान, एसआईपी रिस्क क्या है, इसके बारे में आपको विस्तार पूर्वक जानकारी देंगे तो चलिए आपको इसके बारे में बताते हैं।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>25 Stock market terms for beginners</title><link>/stock-market-terminology/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/stock-market-terminology/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I first entered the share market world, I spend enormous time googling the basic stock market terms which are used in the share market.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although there are many terminologies which a stock market trader should know, they are a handful of stock market terms that are used very often.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This basic domain knowledge of these stock market terms is really important if you want to enter the stock market to succeed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>नए लोग स्टॉक बाज़ार में ऑनलाइन ट्रेडिंग कैसे करें</title><link>/trading-kaise-karte-hain/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/trading-kaise-karte-hain/</guid><description>&lt;p>अगर आपको स्मार्ट तरिके से जल्दी अमीर होना हैं तो आज के वक्त शेअर मार्केट हि एकमात्र करियर हैं जहां आप यह आसानी से अमीर बन सकते हों&lt;/p>
&lt;p>आज हम आपको बताने वाले हैं ट्रेडिंग क्या है, ट्रेडिंग कितने प्रकार के होते हैं, ट्रेडिंग अकाउंट क्या है, आज के इस पोस्ट में आपको वो सब चीजें बताने वाला हूं जिससे आपको ट्रेडिंग की अच्छी खासी जानकारी मिल जाएंगी और आसानी से पैसे कमा सकते हो।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>lump sum investment in mutual fund</title><link>/lump-sum-investment-in-mutual-fund/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/lump-sum-investment-in-mutual-fund/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-lumpsum-investment">What is Lumpsum Investment&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A lumpsum investment is a method where an investment in a mutual fund is made in one go. They are usually made in great amounts, unlike SIPs which are small investment amounts at regular intervals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lumpsum investments do not occur at regular intervals, instead, one can make these at their disposal. For example, let’s say Priya wanted to investment Rs.1,00,000 in a mutual fund.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She didn’t want to split the amount to be put in small investments at regular intervals, since she had surplus money lying idle in her bank account. As Priya is well aware of inflation risk, she decided to put all of it in one go.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>सुकन्या समृद्धि योजना (SSY) बेटियों के बहतर भविष्य के लिए योजना</title><link>/sukanya-samriddhi-yojana/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/sukanya-samriddhi-yojana/</guid><description>&lt;p>आज हम आपको केंद्र सरकार द्वारा शुरू की गई एक योजना से संबंधित जानकारी प्रदान करने जा रहे हैं। जिसका नाम सुकन्या समृद्धि योजना है।&lt;/p>
&lt;p>इस योजना के माध्यम से लाभार्थी द्वारा निवेश करके एकमुश्त राशि बेटी की शिक्षा या फिर शादी के लिए प्राप्त की जा सकती है। इस योजना से संबंधित सभी जरुरी जानकारी आप को दी जाएगी।&lt;/p>
&lt;p>सुकन्या समृद्धि योजना (SSY) बेटियों के भविष्य को उज्जवल एवं सुरक्षित बनाने के लिए सरकार द्वारा इस योजना का संचालन किया जाता है।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Is A Mutual Fund And How Does It Work</title><link>/what-is-mutual-fund/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/what-is-mutual-fund/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today in this article we will talk about What Is a Mutual Fund and How Does It Work,
apart from this, we will talk about more things related to it like investment in Mutual Fund,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Types of Mutual Funds, and Advantages and Disadvantages of Mutual Funds, the benefits of investing in a Mutual Fund will be known in this article.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So let’s start by reading this article carefully about some basic information related to Mutual Fund for Beginners and get good information about What Is a Mutual Fund and How Does It Work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ELSS Fund में निवेश कैसे करे</title><link>/elss-funds-kya-hain/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/elss-funds-kya-hain/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="elss-fund-कय-ह-">ELSS Fund क्या है ?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>ELSS यानि Equity Linked Savings Scheme एक ऐसा म्यूच्यूअल फण्ड इन्वेस्टमेंट ऑप्शन है। जो इन्वेस्टमेंट के साथ एक टैक्स फ्री इन्वेस्टमेंट ऑप्शन है। ELSS एक diversified equity म्यूच्यूअल फण्ड ऑप्शन है जो अपने corpus फंड का maximum पार्ट को इक्विटी में इन्वेस्टमेंट करता है और डाइवर्सिफाइड इक्विटी म्यूच्यूअल फंड होता है। और डाइवर्सिफाइड इक्विटी म्यूच्यूअल फण्ड का मतलब है की यहाँ अलग अलग इंडस्ट्रीज और साइज की कंपनी के शेयर में इन्वेस्टमेंट करता है।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>म्यूचुअल फंड में निवेश कैसे करें</title><link>/mutual-fund-investment-in-hindi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/mutual-fund-investment-in-hindi/</guid><description>&lt;p>क्या आप म्यूचुअल फंड्स की स्कीम में निवेश करते हैं? निवेश करने से पहले म्यूचुअल फंड को जान लेना बहुत जरूरी है। इससे आपको निवेश के फैसले लेने में मदद मिलेगी आइए जानते हैं क्या है म्यूचुअल फंड? हम आपको यह भी बता रहे हैं कि आप म्यूचुअल फंड में कैसे निवेश कर सकते हैं?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>तो यहां पर ‘शीर्ष 10 म्यूचुअल फंड’ के बारे में जानकारी दी जा रही है, जिससे आप मदद ले सकते हैं। अगर आप एक नए म्यूचुअल फंड निवेशक हैं, तो आपके दिमाग में यह सवाल हमेशा आता होगा कि ‘कहां पर निवेश करें और ‘हमें कितना निवेश करना चाहिए?’&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>शेयर बाजार में प्रयोग होने वाले सबसे महत्वपूर्ण 20+ शब्द और उनके अर्थ</title><link>/share-market-terminology/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/share-market-terminology/</guid><description>&lt;p>शेयर मार्केट में प्रयोग होने वाले शब्द और उनके अर्थ जिनसे आप जान सकें शेयर बाज़ार की भाषा जिससे कि आपको इस बाजार और इसकी शब्दावली को समझने में आसानी होगी।&lt;/p>
&lt;p>कई प्रकार के शब्द जो कि शेयर बाजार में प्रयोग किए जाते हैं बाजार कि ट्रेडिंग के बारे में, शेयरों के बारे में या कम्पनियों के बारे में जिनका अर्थ हमें मालूम नहीं होता है। आज समझेंगे शेयर बाजार की भाषा जिससे इस बाजार को समझने में और भी आसानी होगी।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Free Online Finance Calculator in India</title><link>/calculators/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/calculators/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="sip-calculator">SIP Calculator&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/tools/sip-calculator/">&lt;img src="images/2021/10/sip-calculator.png" alt="SIP Calculator">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Systematic Investment Plan (SIP) calculator is an online financial tool that can help to calculate the returns you would earn on your SIP investments.&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="/tools/sip-calculator/" class="rounded btn btn-outline-primary me-2 mb-2" title="SIP Calculator">SIP Calculator&lt;/a>
&lt;h2 id="lumpsum-calculator">Lumpsum Calculator&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/tools/lumpsum-calculator/">&lt;img src="images/2021/10/lumpsum-calculator.png" alt="Lumpsum Calculator">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are you looking to invest a lump-sum amount and get better returns? Here is the answer to invest money in a better way. One of the most lucrative ways of investing in a Mutual Fund is by making a lump sum investment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>आईपीओ क्या है और इसमें कैसे करें निवेश</title><link>/ipo-kya-hota-hain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/ipo-kya-hota-hain/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="आईपओ-कय-ह">आईपीओ क्या है&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>आईपीओ का फुल फॉर्म है- Initial Public Offering (IPO), जब एक कंपनी अपने समान्य स्टॉक या शेयर को पहली बार जनता के लिए जारी करता है तो उसे आईपीओ, इनीशियल पब्लिक ऑफरिंग (सार्वजनिक प्रस्ताव) कहते हैं। लिमिटेड कंपनियों द्वारा ये आईपीओ इसलिए जारी किया जाता है जिससे वह शेयर बाजार में सूचीबद्ध हो सके। शेयर बाजार में सूचीबद्ध होने के बाद कंपनी के शेयरों की खरीद शेयर बाजार में हो सकेगी।&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gold Investment For Beginners</title><link>/gold-investment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/gold-investment/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="gold-investment-for-beginners">Gold Investment for Beginners&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today in this article we will talk about Gold Investment for Beginners, apart from this we will talk about more things related to it like investment in gold, how to buy gold?, buy from jewelery shop, or online, sovereign gold bond(s).gb) What is?, What is Gold ETF? What is Gold Mutual Fund?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gold Mutual Funds vs Gold ETFs, is it necessary to have a demat account to invest in gold, the benefits of investing in gold will be known in this article.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Basic knowledge of share market</title><link>/share-market-basic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/share-market-basic/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="basic-knowledge-of-share-market">Basic knowledge of share market&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today in this article we will get some basic information related to the share market, like what is a share, why does a company need a share, how is a company&amp;rsquo;s stock list, how does a company earn money in the stock market, and we share shares. How to earn money by investing in the market. What is SEBI, what is stock exchange, what is Nifty and SENSEX, how can we buy and sell shares in the stock market, do we have to pay tax in the stock market.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is share market</title><link>/share-market/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/share-market/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="information-about-share-market">Information about share market&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this article, we will know some important things related to share market, out of which what is share market.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How to start share market, how to invest in share market, who is called share holder, why company sells shares, what is an investor, how to buy and sell shares.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Intraday Trading, Swing Trading, Long Term Investment, Trading Vs Investment What is better, How to buy Shares, What is Demat Account, Advantages of Demat Account, How to Open Demat Account, How to Lose in Share Market&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Investment in English</title><link>/investment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/investment/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-investment">What Is Investment&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Investment means investment in which we invest any of our things for some time.In which we expect more profit from it in the coming time, it is called investment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Time, money or any other such thing in investment, which should not be used for yourself at that time and keep it by blocking it.In the hope that there will be more profit from it in the coming time.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>